Guide to the Ruth Carter Slack family papers, 1873-1990 MS 430
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Ruth Carter Slack family papers
1873-1990
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Slack, Ruth Carter
MS 430
3 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
This collection consists of the personal and family papers of Houstonian Ruth Carter Slack, including diaries, correspondence, personal travel memorabilia, and memorabilia from her personal life, such as inventories, lists and address books. Also in the collection are her photo collections, hospital records, course notes, and documentation of the Carter and Slack family history.
Biographical / Historical
Ruth Carter Slack was born into Houston's prominent Carter family. Her father, Clarence L. Carter (1869-1936), was a second generation partner at Baker Botts Law firm. After graduating from University of Texas Law School in 1891, he began working as an attorney in Livingston, TX, then moved to Houston in 1902 and engaged in general individual practice. C.L. Carter joined Baker Botts in 1907 and became partner in 1909. He stayed with the firm, mainly working as a specialist in Railroad Law, until his death in 1936. During his career, he was Vice President and director of the Groveton, Lufkin, and Northern Railway Co. and was director of the Union National Bank. Carter was also elected President of the Harris County Bar Association in 1908. On January 11, 1893, Carter married Alice Lyle Winston, and they had five children, including Ruth, the youngest. Ruth was born, raised, and educated in Houston, and was married to Samuel Morris Slack. She spent time traveling and kept diaries, photos and correspondence to chronicle her trips to Ireland, Europe, and the Middle East. Ruth Carter Slack continued her education into her adulthood, and enjoyed gardening, philanthropy and spending time with her family.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of two diaries and correspondence, such as cards, letters and postcards, as well as travel memorabilia from her trips to Europe, Ireland and the Middle East. Extensive documentation of the Carter, Slack, and Casperson family histories, including correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs, and family history books, is also present. Memorabilia from Ruth Carter Slack's personal life, such as lists, inventories, address books, and items from her early life and included, as well as a record of her hospital visit in 1990.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Ameritrust via trust officer Mark Farrell in 1993.
Index Terms
Subjects
Travelers' writings; Women
Document Types
diaries; photographs; corrrespondence
Subjects (Persons)
Slack, Ruth Carter; Slack, Samuel Morris; Slack, Wood; Carter, Ernest T.; Carter, Clarence Leon; Carter, Winston; Carter, John W.; Caspersen, Clare Carter
- Series I: Personal Memorabilia, 1961-1990, 30027
  - Diary, 1961, 30049 (Box 1)
  - Diary, Ireland, 1965, 30048 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 30047 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Europe and Mid-East, 1955, 30046 (Box 1)
  - Early memorabilia, 30045 (Box 1)
  - Course Notes, 1967-1972, 30044 (Box 1)
  - Course Notes, 1977-1983, 30043 (Box 1)
  - Religious Books, 30042 (Box 1)
  - Address Books and Lists, 30041 (Box 1)
  - Daily Hospital Record, 1990, 30040 (Box 1)
  - Party Lists, Inventories, 30039 (Box 1)
  - Calling Cards, 30038 (Box 1)
  - "RCS" Stationery die, 30037 (Box 1)
  - Jewelry inventory, 30036 (Box 1)
  - Passports, 30035 (Box 1)
  - Souvenir Postcards, Blank, 30034 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Morris Slack: Schooling, 30033 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Morris Slack: Military Memorabilia, 30032 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Book: Ernest T. Carter, 30031 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Book: John W. Carter, 30030 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Book: Clare Carter Caspersen, 30029 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Book: Samuel Morris Slack, 30028 (Box 1)
- Series II: Family History, 1873-1987, 30020
  - Slack Family History Book, 1979, 30026 (Box 2)
  - Slack, Wood, 1873-1946, 30025 (Box 2)
  - Carter, Winston, 1929-1987, 30024 (Box 2)
  - Family Real Estate, 1910-1973, 30023 (Box 2)
  - Casperson Estate- Broadacres Home, 1914-1973, 30022 (Box 2)
  - Carter-Capersen Wedding, 30021 (Box 2)
- Series III: Photographs, 1889-1988, 29985
  - Early Family, 1918-1955, 30019 (Box 3)
  - Early Family, 1919, 30018 (Box 3)
  - Early Family, n.d., 30017 (Box 3)
  - John Winston Carter, 1952-1963, 30016 (Box 3)
  - Carter Girls, 30015 (Box 3)
  - Clare Carter, 1917, 30014 (Box 3)
  - Ruth Carter Slack, 1913-1982; 30013 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Morris Slack. 1918-1926, 30012 (Box 3)
  - Vacations, 1889-1968, 30011 (Box 3)
  - Italian Trip, 1962, 30010 (Box 3)
  - Snapshots, 1983-1985, 30009 (Box 3)
  - Individuals, 1965-1972, 30008 (Box 3)
  - Groups, 1955-1986, 30007 (Box 3)
  - Groups, 1899, 30006 (Box 3)
  - Groups, n.d., 30005 (Box 3)
  - Rice University Archi-Arts Ball, 1930, 30004 (Box 3)
  - Early Family, 30003 (Box 3)
  - Brides, 30002 (Box 3)
  - Clarence Leon Carter, 1919-?, 30001 (Box 3)
  - Andrew J. Caspersen, 30000 (Box 3)
  - Wood Family, 29999 (Box 3)
  - Sisters and brother-in-law, 29998 (Box 3)
  - S. Morris Slack's mother, 1931, 29997 (Box 3)
  - Houses, 1929-1988, 29996 (Box 3)
  - Ruth Carter Slack, 29995 (Box 4)
  - Clarence Leon Carter, 29994 (Box 4)
  - Andrew J. Caspersen, 29993 (Box 4)
  - Bride and attendants, unidentified, 29992 (Box 4)
  - Carter sister, 29991 (Box 4)
  - Oversize: Girl's Basketball Team, unidentified, 29990 (Box 4)
  - Oversize: Dinner Party with C.L. Carter at center of table, 29989 (Box 4)
  - Oversize: Ruth Carter Slack, 29988 (Box 4)
  - Oversize: Bride [possibly Ruth Carter Slack], 29987 (Box 4)
  - Samuel Morris Slack's Rice Institute diploma, June 9, 1930, 29986 (Box 4)
- Series IV: Clothing, 1928
  - Debutante dress, 1928 (Box 5)